Matthew Low

https://mattchrlw.github.io

https://www.linkedin.com/in/matthew-c-low

2nd year mathematics and computer science student at the University of Queensland with experience in a variety of languages and environments as well as strong mathematical and statistical skills. My interests lie in algorithms, machine learning, operations research, optimisation, front-end web development and graphic design.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Mathematics and Computer Science

Brisbane, Australia

Mobile: 0435 930 130

Email: m.low@uqconnect.edu.au

The University of Queensland; GPA: 6.00/7.00

Feb. 2018 - Dec. 2021

- o Major: Machine Learning
- o Relevant Coursework: Numerical Linear Algebra & Optimisation, Operations Research & Mathematical Planning, Statistical Modelling & Analysis, Advanced Calculus & Linear Algebra II, Mathematical Analysis, Probability & Statistics, Algorithms & Data Structures, Computer Systems Principles & Programming

High School

Brisbane, Australia

St Peters Lutheran College; OP: 3

Jan. 2013 - Nov. 2017

o Subjects: Information Technology Systems (Dux), Mathematics B, Physics, Information Processing Technology, Accounting, English

EXPERIENCE

Start-Up China Summer Program Dalian Neusoft University of Information

Dalian, P.R. China

Jun. 2019 - Jul. 2019

o IT Innovation and Entrepreneurship Program: Prototyped and developed a software product for the Chinese market, under the Australian Government's New Colombo Plan scholarship grant for students studying in the Asia-Pacific region. This product was a nutrition application for managing daily intakes and scanning & recognising foods using machine learning.

Robotics Mentor

Brisbane, Australia

St Peters Lutheran College

May. 2019 - Present

o Mentoring: Assisting students from Years 5-12 in the extra-curricular Robotics program at the college with programming and building Lego Mindstorms EV3 robots.

Information Technology Prefect

Brisbane, Australia

St Peters Lutheran College

Sep. 2016 - Sep. 2017

- o Events: Assisted with the usage of technology in various events. Acted as an informal assistant if any technical difficulties arose during school events.
- o Student IT Helpdesk: Assisted students with issues with their computer, such as software installation and email
- o Computer Club: Taught some basic computer skills to junior high as well as senior school students such as programming in JavaScript and using Photoshop.

PROJECTS

- Orange (group project): A nutrition application for managing daily intakes and scanning & recognising foods using machine learning, developed with Django and Bootstrap.
- YeetBeat (group project): A music guessing game, synchronously delivering snippets of audio to multiple users developed with Heroku, Bootstrap and NodeJS.
- PyFoil: A Python script that parses and processes airfoil data for use in aerodynamic analysis, using subprocess to interface with an existing command-line application XFOIL.
- measure-theory: A website and associated Python script that parses, calculates and provides song chart breakdowns for the popular dance game In the Groove (similar to Dance Dance Revolution).
- Blackboard Refresh: A CSS/JavaScript userscript that re-styles and provides enhancements to the existing UQ Blackboard interface.
- Java 3D Game: A Java third-person 3D block building game based on JavaFX and implemented using object-oriented programming principles.

OTHER

- Awards:
 - o 1st Place Newcomers: UQCS Hackathon 2019, UQ Computing Society
 - $\circ\,$ 1st Place: Industry vs Student Showdown 2019, QUT Code Network
- Languages: Python, Java, MATLAB, C, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, LATEX, Lua
- Technologies: Git, Bash, Vim, Unix/Linux, Gurobi, PHPMyAdmin, Corona SDK, LÖVE2D, RStudio
- Applications: Photoshop, Illustrator, Animate, Dreamweaver, Microsoft Office
- Software engineering skills: Object-oriented programming, database design, unit & mutation testing
- Quantitative skills: Linear, integer & dynamic programming, calculus, lin. alg., discrete maths, statistics
- Certifications: Adobe Certified Associate in Photoshop, Adobe Certified Associate in Animate
- Extracurriculars: Member of UQ Computing Society, QUT Code Network & Mathematics Students Society